<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Candlegraph</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Candlegraph</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Candle Burn Times v1</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025/07/28/candle-burn-times-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025/07/28/candle-burn-times-v1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before this project started, I enjoyed scented candles as much as the next person - well, maybe a bit more than the next person - but the thought of taking measurements had not yet crossed my mind. As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned, I wanted to increase my Excel skills, and candles just so happened to be there. The very first candle I measured was one from Paddywax Apothecary, probably because it was the most recent candle I had purchased. The scent was Patchouli and Tobacco, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of the candles in my first presentation, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll have a separate post about it somewhere down the line. While I don&amp;rsquo;t burn candles every single day anymore, at the time, I was deep into my new obsession and quickly went down the data-gathering rabbit hole. Soon, I had recorded information about burn times, price, and weight from five different candles, and it was time to start making some of my favorite things - charts and graphs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next New R Markdown</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025/07/28/next-new-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025/07/28/next-new-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;r-markdown&#34;&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34;&gt;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you click the &lt;strong&gt;Knit&lt;/strong&gt; button a document will be generated that includes both content as well as the output of any embedded R code chunks within the document. You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;summary(cars)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##      speed           dist       &#xA;##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  &#xA;##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  &#xA;##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  &#xA;##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  &#xA;##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  &#xA;##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;including-plots&#34;&gt;Including Plots&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots, for example:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New R Markdown</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025/07/27/new-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025/07/27/new-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;this-is-a-new-test-post&#34;&gt;This is a new test post.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Italics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/infographics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/infographics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to more information about candles than you probably ever hoped to know! I started this project as a way to use one of my hobbies – scented candles – to expand my knowledge of Excel. From there, it has grown into a full data analytics project, including the use of such tools as SQL and Tableau, both of which I’m still learning. In fact, it’s fair to say that I’m still learning about most of this, even how to best measure and analyze the data I get from burning candles. There may (read: probably will) be times when you say, “Hey wait, that’s wrong.” Please bear with me – hopefully we can learn from each other!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Candlegraph!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to more information about candles than you probably ever hoped to know! I started this project as a way to use one of my hobbies – scented candles – to expand my knowledge of Excel. From there, it has grown into a full data analytics project, including the use of such tools as SQL and Tableau, both of which I’m still learning. In fact, it’s fair to say that I’m still learning about most of this, even how to best measure and analyze the data I get from burning candles. There may (read: probably will) be times when you say, “Hey wait, that’s wrong.” Please bear with me – hopefully we can learn from each other!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing with R</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025/07/24/playing-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025/07/24/playing-with-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, we&amp;rsquo;ll load in our libraries. I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;code&gt;library(here)&lt;/code&gt; on the advice of Jenny Bryan from her &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidyverse.org/blog/2017/12/workflow-vs-script/&#34;&gt;Project-oriented workflow&lt;/a&gt; post on Tidyverse. This is just to organize my project into a folder in order to keep it self-contained and portable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;# loading libraries&#xA;library(readr)&#xA;library(dplyr)&#xA;library(tidyverse)&#xA;library(here)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next, we&amp;rsquo;ll load in the data. This comes from 4 tabs of a Google Sheets file on which I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded my candle research. Variables include things such as the price and weight of a candle, as well as how long it burned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2023/12/25/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2023/12/25/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this project, I had no idea what I was doing, and I didn’t even know it would turn into a project. I just wanted something fun to work on while trying to figure out how adults use Excel. That is, for something other than just organizing a collection or making a schedule. It turns out that’s all a lot of people use Excel for, and there’s nothing wrong with that. Still, I wanted to take advantage of all spreadsheets have to offer, and using the data I was already gathering (but not yet recording) seemed like a good place to start. I figured that doing something fun alongside my Excel education would keep me interested and motivated, and in that I was correct. In fact it ended up growing into something much more, but in this post I want to focus on how it all began.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Candlegraph!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2023/09/10/welcome-to-candlegraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2023/09/10/welcome-to-candlegraph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to Candlegraph! My name is Terry, and I love scented candles. They’re a great way to turn your house into a warm and inviting home. However, not all scented candles are created equal, which is the idea behind this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you exactly when it happened, but somewhere along the way I started measuring how long certain candles would burn for, and how much value I was getting from these (sometimes expensive) candles. An Excel sheet was born, and out of that, a PowerPoint presentation and Toastmasters speech entitled &lt;strong&gt;Candle Burn Times: A Value Proposition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
