<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Candlegraph</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Candlegraph</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2023/12/25/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2023/12/25/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this project, I had no idea what I was doing, and I didn’t even know it would turn into a project. I just wanted something fun to work on while trying to figure out how adults use Excel. That is, for something other than just organizing a collection or making a schedule. It turns out that’s all a lot of people use Excel for, and there’s nothing wrong with that. Still, I wanted to take advantage of all spreadsheets have to offer, and using the data I was already gathering (but not yet recording) seemed like a good place to start. I figured that doing something fun alongside my Excel education would keep me interested and motivated, and in that I was correct. In fact it ended up growing into something much more, but in this post I want to focus on how it all began.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Candlegraph!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2023/09/10/welcome-to-candlegraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2023/09/10/welcome-to-candlegraph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to Candlegraph! My name is Terry, and I love scented candles. They’re a great way to turn your house into a warm and inviting home. However, not all scented candles are created equal, which is the idea behind this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you exactly when it happened, but somewhere along the way I started measuring how long certain candles would burn for, and how much value I was getting from these (sometimes expensive) candles. An Excel sheet was born, and out of that, a PowerPoint presentation and Toastmasters speech entitled &lt;strong&gt;Candle Burn Times: A Value Proposition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
